[Music]
it is a chilly february afternoon in the
bookstore and after the holiday rush
things have settled into a slower quiet
pace that i thoroughly enjoy
in this video i thought i'd share a bit
about how i manage my money in a rural
area there were definitely certain costs
living out here that i thought may be
interesting to share
now there's really no way i could cover
everything and get into enough detail
just in one video but i will attempt to
speak on a few things that i prioritize
in regards to money management
i will discuss things more in detail
about 10 minutes in
so you can skip to that if you wish
[Music]
so i must begin with food because it is
one of the larger costs that i budget
for and is always several hundred
dollars a month
usually about what i make working at my
bookstore once a week
as you may know from watching past
videos i've had a history of not always
prioritizing my health
it is an ongoing quest to eat quality
foods and not just give into my sweet
tooth when it's convenient
noticing my frugal tendencies early on i
remember my parents always saying that
saving money when possible is great but
try to never compromise your health i
now see the wisdom in their words and
agree that if at all possible we should
prioritize feeding our bodies well and
getting good sleep it's such a crucial
foundation
[Music]
in addition when i have a new home i
definitely want to buy some extra food
to store for emergencies we are rural
enough that it's possible after an
earthquake or other situation we could
be cut off from supply chains so i
really do want to be ready just in case
so i expect to spend extra money on that
when the time comes
[Music]
one expense i didn't anticipate when
moving here was the cost of keeping my
car in good condition i need to usually
change the tires for winter and then
regular tires for the rest of the year
and of course those need to be replaced
rural roads can be hard on the car
causing it to need repairs more often
and then of course there's a very high
likelihood that you can get into an
accident with a deer on the road
thankfully i don't have to drive too
much i don't really go on road trips or
travel very far so i only really have to
fill up on gas once or twice a month
[Music]
do
seriously
[Music]
in regards to my wardrobe i don't buy
new clothes very often i try to limit it
and just use what i have as much as
possible
you will see that i wear certain fast
fashion items that i have owned long
before i became informed about how
important it is to consider where your
clothes comes from
but i also have to admit that i don't
purchase sustainable fashion very often
i have found that the options available
for tall people like myself are limited
and very very expensive
and i'm just not able to rationalize
spending hundreds of dollars on a single
piece of clothing i really do try to
just focus on using what i already have
and just wearing it until it's all worn
out
i also try to buy used clothing as much
as possible if you ever noticed
something particularly unique in one of
these videos it's usually because it is
second hand i find a lot of interesting
things at thrift shops and it is one of
my favorite places to go
i try to keep in mind that some of the
most sustainable and mindful practices
we can do in regards to how we consume
is to simply use what we already have to
be grateful for it using it fully and
not be excessive
i try to apply that mentality on many
things in my life financial and
otherwise
[Music]
so i was tidying up my house the other
day
and i realized that i had about eight
full-size candles like this size so
i thought that was probably a little bit
excessive
but um i definitely am a candle lover so
i just kind of decided you know what
eight candles it's all right i just
won't get any more i went to go meet a
friend
and she actually had a new year's gift
for me and it was a candle and then i
went to my mailbox down the road and
there was a big package waiting for me
and i realized it was a gift box from
the mythology candle company which i've
bought candles from and i love
and they gifted me the entire spring
collection which is shire themed which
was so exciting
so i had a blast opening it and smelling
them all and i
was like oh my goodness this is like six
new full-sized candles it's okay it's
all right
it's okay you know it's not a problem
unless you think it is right
and then the story gets even better i
went to my p.o box in the town next to
me which i check at least once a month
or so
and the postmaster said that i had a
couple packages there i just opened them
and they're from you guys and
two of you lovely lovely people sent me
more candles
i think within 24 hours
i have gone from owning eight candles to
like 30 candles
orange spice and vanilla
oh my gosh
i think that's my favorite
anyway i laughed so hard when i opened
those packages it is the sweetest thing
to just
accept that together we are creating
this problem because
if i'm turning into the crazy candle
lady i might as well make it a thing and
you know share with you guys my recent
discoveries woodwicks cotton wicks soy
wax beeswax i could talk about candles a
lot a lot quite a bit the mythology
candle company is very very sweet and
they definitely started me on a path
where i'm gonna end up i don't know
but i will keep you updated
so moving on from my day
i was reticent to make a video talking a
little bit more about finances i think
sometimes it's a
a very complex subject to
talk about i think people have a lot of
feelings associated with money i
definitely do i thought it would be
worth kind of mentioning
some things that i try to prioritize
every month maybe it would give you a
little bit of a perspective of
how i manage my money in the countryside
even though i feel
financially stable thank goodness now
it's definitely a relationship i wanted
to improve with myself and my finances
not seeing money as an enemy or
something that needs to be a constant
source of
fear
the vast majority of people i
i'm close with that are kind of spread
out all over the place all
seem to have equal difficulties finding
affordable places to live
whether they're in the city or in the
countryside you know and definitely here
i just wake up every day being so
grateful i have a roof over my head it
means so much to start a new journey
with luke and to know that we hopefully
will have a place that
will be ours i'm so aware too that
if my life had just been the slightest
bit different it would have never been
possible to do that and so i'm just
so happy that i will be able to stay and
live in the valley i love so much
when it is so hard
sometimes to find places to live that
you can afford this is an interesting
area in the state it is the poorest
county
and yet this area in particular is a
tourist hub so
it's kind of a lot of
interesting kind of contradictory
elements
a local author wrote a book called
dividing paradise on rural inequality
and it was really interesting and it
really what i i took from and i think a
lot of locals have taken from it is how
important it is to reach out to your
community to be active in your community
to give what you can and to do
everything possible to support not only
the
people here but the wildlife and the
valley some role models i had growing up
were people who really fought for
preserving nature some that come to mind
is of course beatrix potter john moore
jane goodall
they're really fascinating individuals
and i
took a lot from their mission to try to
preserve the beauty preserve
all this incredible landscape for the
future and so every month that is
something i try to prioritize to find
ways to give back especially through my
nature conservancy which has done some
amazing things in this valley especially
after the wildfires i share this because
i personally have found that getting
involved in something you care about
in any way you can whether you are able
to get involved in a big way or in a
small way or just
volunteer some time it's
just so fulfilling and it's just amazing
to think that you can be part of
building a future i think a really
positive influence teaching young
children had on me was that
i saw the future in their eyes i saw how
important it was
for me to be an example to them
not just tell them what i care about but
show them and i want them to see that i
want them to see that
that it is our responsibility to
cultivate hope and to cultivate
that positivity
and to really be there for them and our
little people i think really
rely on us so much for an example on how
to see the world
because of the challenges finding
rentals in this area i have noticed that
many young people do get quite creative
i've met several people who moved to the
area and just lived in trailers while
they worked full time
and eventually through kind of community
connections they were able to find a
place to live
and
that is really interesting and inspiring
and it's really fun to see young people
getting so creative and and finding ways
to
uh little by little work towards their
dreams and that's definitely something
i've taken to heart you know it's just
baby steps it might take a year five
years ten years a lifetime
to
get to where you want to go
i will say that when i lived in the city
definitely as a very young adult i had
many friends who
would live in situations that were
not very safe for the sake of saving
money and that is definitely something i
kind of inadvertently through naivety
and through lack of experience
got myself into as well when i was in
the city i
rented an apartment that
thinking back on it was probably rented
out illegally to me though i
didn't really understand that at the
time all i knew was that it was a lot
more affordable than other places and it
was a very unclean space it had a lot of
rat infestations
there was a very high chance of getting
your food contaminated in the kitchen
because of that
and
the room i was in
was
not insulated and it had just one really
small window because it was in an attic
and you couldn't get out of that window
in an emergency
and that was something that had never
occurred to me until one day a drunk
driver backed into our gas pipe and
flooded the house
a firefighter actually woke me up out of
my bed
he stormed through the door and just
about gave me a heart attack i was
already feeling quite dizzy at the time
because i'd just been
breathing in all this gas that was just
flowing into the room and had nowhere to
go it was just kind of piling up in
there and
that moment will always stick with me
for the rest of my life i will see
firefighters is absolute superheroes the
reason i am sharing this story is
because i moved into that apartment
without really
seriously taking into consideration the
question of safety
and a big part of moving there was
because it was affordable
and
it's sad to think that for the sake of
being able to save a couple hundred
dollars every month
i was willing to risk my life like that
and it was a big wake-up call it was
shortly after that experience that i
decided that i really needed to find a
new job and a new place to live and that
i needed to call up my mama and tell her
my story and and
ask for help and stop being so stubborn
and
i am
forever grateful that i had a family
that was willing to help me and was able
to help me and
i don't know what i would have done if i
hadn't had them there
i don't know what i would have done so
yeah
the moral of this story is
whoever you are whatever place you are
in life i hope that if you are able to
do so
that you always keep your safety and
your health into consideration
but yeah take take care of yourself you
are worthy of help you are worthy of
health
all these things are the foundation of
you know working towards those dreams
trying to find peace trying to find
healing
but yes there has been some progress on
applying for a loan thankfully it does
seem to be going uh well for us so far
i was a bit worried because
usually banks need two years worth of
tax returns and while i was able to
show the income from my business last
year the year before
i was still a teacher that put me in a
financial bracket where i wouldn't be
approved for a loan with those two years
of tax returns so i had to wait until i
filed my taxes for this year in order to
be approved on my own but thankfully
between luke and i it does seem like
we're still going to get approved
because he's had a stable job working as
a surveyor for several years in this
area
and he's such a dedicated and hard
worker and
honestly thanks to him kind of all this
is possible so
yeah i'm i'm so proud of him
but yeah um so we will see how it goes i
am so excited about all of it and of
course i need to conclude this by saying
thank you to all of you you guys have
changed my life
completely changed my life you have
allowed me to make a living
through my art
through
sharing things i love through this
valley
and
i cannot thank you enough
all right
well
i think i have talked more than enough
maybe too much but i hope you're all uh
well
i will see you very very soon and take
care i am sending my love
goodbye